# **Tyler Hall**

Pittsburgh, PA | thall2980@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog

### **Full Stack Web Developer**

I am a Full Stack Web Developer and Software Engineer experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in Biology and patient care in a hospital setting. I possess the drive and capability to quickly master new and challenging topics in full stack web development. I have built my technical skills on valuing efficiency without sacrificing quality in addition to possessing strong and effective communication when working with others on projects. I plan to hone these skills as I enter the tech world and demonstrate my newfound passion for constructing and optimizing full stack web applications.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, React.js, HTML, CSS, Active Record, GitHub, Ubuntu, and npm.

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Art Spot - GitHub | Demo

A social media app for artists to post artwork, comment, and like other user's artwork.

- Created a backend API using Ruby on Rails following the MVC pattern with a React.js frontend.
- Implemented an aliased user model to create a follower-following relationship.
- Utilized session cookies to authorize/authenticate user accounts.

### Groove Hound - GitHub | Demo

A concert tracking app that displays upcoming concerts and bands.

- Constructed a backend API using Ruby on Rails following the MVC pattern with a React.js frontend.
- Utilized session cookies to authorize/authenticate user accounts.
- Implemented the Mantine library in addition to vanilla CSS to style the application.

### Wagging Walkers - Front End | Back End | Demo

A dog walking service where users can register their dogs and create appointments.

- Constructed a backend API through Sinatra with two models relating to each other via a many-to-many relationship.
- Utilized React for the front end of the application to display the database entries.
- Implemented full CRUD capabilities that persisted through the backend.

#### League of Legends Worlds 2022 - GitHub | Demo

An application to display the 2022 League of Legends world tournament information with a message board feature.

- Created a local JSON server to act as the backend endpoint for fetch requests with a fully-fleshed React.js frontend.
- Implemented conditional rendering through the use of state and user actions.
- Organized the application as a single page to limit HTTP requests through client-side routing using React Router.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### University of Pittsburgh Medical Center Presbyterian Hospital

Pittsburgh, PA

Patient Care Technician

08/2017 - 08/2022

- Responsible for efficiently managing an assignment of 10-20 patients in an inpatient physical rehabilitation hospital unit with patient diagnoses ranging from stroke to organ transplant.
- Worked directly with nurses to ensure patients' medical and personal needs were met as they completed their activities of daily living.
- Accurately measured and recorded patients' vital signs, collected specimens for testing, and ensured patient safety when transferring from bed to wheelchair or ambulating in the hallways.

#### **Noodles and Company**

Pittsburgh, PA

Saute Line Cook

01/2016 - 08/2017

- Ensured quality product standards while matching the cadence of total sales peaking at \$9000 in a single day.
- Trained six new hires on the saute line with emphasis on efficiency, quality, and cohesion with the rest of the kitchen.

### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School

Remote, Live Program

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and React.js programming.

08/2022 - 12/2022

**University of Pittsburgh** 

Pittsburgh, PA

Bachelor of Science - Biological Sciences

08/2010 - 04/2014